ASHISH MISHRA

Software Developer



+91 73030 19154











Mumbai, Maharashtra

SUMMARY

Highly dedicated and skilled Python Software developer with more than 4+ years of experience offering advanced software development expertise. I am Software developer with proven experience in Python, Django, backend development, AI, cloud applications, and data analytics. Seeking a mid-level role to leverage skills for organizational growth.

EDUCATION

Mumbai University

Bacholer's Of Engineering in Information Technology. 2012 – 2016

Maharashtra State Board

XII in Science Stream 2010 – 2012

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Programming Proficient** Python **Competent**: Embeded C, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Libraries / Frameworks / Tools Django, Flask, DRF(Django Rest Framework), VS code, PowerShell.
- Databases MySQL, Oracle, SQL.
- Systems / Platforms Git, Github, Linux, Docker, AWS.

PROJECTS

- **Responsive Portfolio:** Developed using Django, HTML, CSS, and SOLite.
- **Zoom Clone:** Interactive Clone webapp using Django framework to make videocalls and share screen.
- **Covid-19 Live Updates**: Responsive web app fetching live data using Rapid API and Flask.
- **BigApple's Edu**: Platform offering free courses and certifications by using Django and SQL.
- **BigApple's Edu ChatBot**: Chatbot for course recommendations using IBM Watson.
- **To-Do List App**: CRUD operations with user authentication using Django.

CERTIFICATIONS

Python for Data Science and AI (IBM) | Python Basics (University of Michigan) | Python Certification ITVedant (ClassroomTraining). | Databases and SQL for Data Science (IBM) | Web Development (Johns Hopkins University) | Algorithm-I (Stanford University) | Django (PluralSight) | Web Development (Udemy) | Build ChatBot Using IBM Watson (Udemy) | Portfolio Website with HTML and CSS.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WhiteHat Jr | Byju's.

Senior Associate Developer (Curriculum) | May 2021 - Feb 2024

- Utilized 2.5+ years of experience with Python and Django for backend development and API design to integrate with systems.
- Manage cutting-edge technologies to improve legacy applications and collaborated with Front-end developers to integrate userfacing elements with server side logic.
- Developed a customer issue resolution product, reducing manual resolution time by 55%.
- Conducted advanced research and development in web development, AI, cloud computing, and machine learning.
- Designed, developed, and maintained applications and plugins using Unreal Engine and IoT Applications.
- Collaborated with stakeholders and developers to implement new features and enhance software capabilities.

Hexaware Technologies.

Executive Administrator | May 2019 - Feb 2020

- Defined and set development, test, release, update, and support processes for DevOps operations.
- Reviewing and Auditing Data and Application through various internal app.
- Troubleshot and debugged issues with applications and plugins to ensure seamless functionality.
- Maintained Active Directory & user backups.
- Managed system security and resolved Windows OS issues.

HCL Technologies.

System Administrator | Sept 2016 - Feb 2018

- Handling Datacenter and Defining and setting development, test, release, update, and support processes for DevOps operation.
- Maintaining Active Directory & Backups of Users.
- Maintaining Security of system by Antivirus management.
- Use to handle & resolve Windows OS (7, 8.1, 10) related issues.
- Creating Database, Monitoring Database.
- Managing User Accounts, Tablespaces, etc.

Declaration: I hereby declare that the above written particulars are to the best of my knowledge and belief.